We've discussed the three main considerations when you're
我们已经讨论了在选择分组单元时
choosing a unit of diversion.
需要考虑的三个主要因素
Are there any other questions to keep in mind when you're choosing a population?
关于选择总体 我们需要注意哪些方面？
>> Yeah, so first you want to think about the fact that,
首先 你需要考虑的是
in anything but event diversion, if you do cookie diversion,
在不使用事件作为分组方式时 例如你将 cookie 或设备作用分组方式
if you do device diversion, you're really looking at proxies for users.
那么你实际上是在观察用户的代理
And that means you're going to have one group of users on the A side of your
也就是说 你将为实验的 A 组和 B 组
experiment and one group on the B side.
分别分配一组用户
Now if you do event based diversion,
如果使用事件作为分组方式
you can end up with the mix of the same people on both sides.
那么相同的用户可能同时分到两组中
So you have to be pretty careful in this case to make sure you haven't
在这种情况下 你得非常小心
inadvertently mismatched your users.
注意不要错误地匹配用户
There are some other options.
也有一些其他选项
There's what's called an intra-user experiment.
例如有一种实验叫作用户内实验
That typically means that you expose the same user to this feature being on and
在某个功能上线时以及下线后
of over time, and
你针对相同用户进行实验
you actually analyze how they behave in different time windows.
分析他们在不同时间段内的行为
This has some pitfalls, for example,
这种实验有一些缺陷
you have to be really careful that you choose a comparable time window.
例如你必须小心选择具有可比性的时间段
You don't want to do this in the two weeks before Christmas and
你肯定不能在圣诞节前两周中开展这个实验
then have them behave very differently in the second part.
因为在实验的第二阶段 用户行为可能发生重大变化
The other issues with a lot of features, you have a frustration or a learning
在实验许多功能时 你还可能遇到用户学习使用新功能的问题
problem, where people learn to use the particular feature in the first two
用户在头两周学会了使用那个特定功能
weeks and then when you turn it off they're like, why did my website change?
但然后你又将那个功能下线 用户可能会觉得很困惑 网站怎么发生变化了？
So you can get some different behaviors as a result.
这时候用户的行为就可能发生变化
For certain other types of applications like search ranking, preferences or,
对于某些类型的应用 例如搜索排名、用户优选之类的应用
you know, other things where you actually have a ranked order list,
你在其中要设置排名列表
you have an option of running what's called an interleaved experiment, where
你可以选择开展交叉实验
you actually expose the same user to the A and the B side at the same time.
你同时为实验的 A 组和 B 组分配相同的用户
And typically this only works in cases where you're looking at
不过这种实验通常只适用于观察
reordering a list.
对列表进行重新排序
There's more information in the instructor's notes
如果想要详细了解这些
if you want to follow up on that.
请参阅讲师备注中提供的额外信息
But what we mainly talk about in A/B testing
但是 在 A/B 测试中
is what's called inter-user experiments.
我们主要讨论用户间实验
That means you've got different people on the A side and on the B side.
也就是为实验的 A 组和 B 组分配不同的用户
We'll talk in a minute about a refinement of that called a cohort.
我们稍后将讨论如何调整队列
In a cohort, you try to match up your entering class so
在队列中 你将尝试根据某些条件来匹配入组的用户
at least you have roughly the same parameters in your two user groups.
至少要让两组用户的某些参数较为类似
In medical and drug treatment trials and things like that,
在医学和药物治疗之类的试验中
they'll take this even a step further, and they'll actually match up
人们通常会采用更严格的匹配条件
patients in the trial based on demographic information, age,
他们可能根据人口统计学信息、年龄、病历等
medical history, and they'll actually do a paired analysis.
来匹配受试者 并进行配对分析
But because of what we don't know about people on the internet, we're,
但是 因为我们并不了解互联网上的用户
we don't even know if these are real people.
我们甚至无法确定他们是不是真的用户
You basically never see that in internet experiments.
所以在互联网实验中 我们基本上不可能这么做